(Transcribed by TurboScribe. Go Unlimited to remove this message.) 9.43pm. So I'm gonna define this properly.
What do you mean by properly?
I'm going to be defining a microVM.
A microVM is, let's talk about the fundamental
problems of microVM.
What is the fundamental problem of microVM?
A micro virtual machine.
A micro a native service in an unsupported
environment.
How to run a native service in an
unsupported environment?
That's the question.
What is a microVM?
A microVM allows you to run an unsupported
service in an unsupported, a native service in
an unsupported environment.
It's micro-isolation.
Primarily, a microVM serves as not a bridge
but actual native service in an isolated environment,
in an unsupported, isolated environment.
It works because it's beautiful.
It's a continualization.
It's like a docker.
You have docker.
Docker works in a way that is, docker
works by containing, it basically works, uses native
services to contain for environment.
A microVM doesn't use, and the difference between
docker and a microVM, my mispronunciation of microscript,
M for Mike, I for Indigo, C for
Charlie, R for Romeo, O for Oscar, is
that a microVM does not use the native
libraries.
For example, it's a plug and play system.
Plug and play system.
It's basically, you instal it and you use
the service.
You plug and you play, you plug and
you plug, you attach it, you attach it
or you host it, and then you serve
the services directly without using any, only the
native tools that are provided by a target
language, like a programming language.
An example I'm going to give you is
docker.
The problem with pro docker is that docker
containerise everything, but uses windows containers or uses
windows containers or linux containers to contain for
an instance of architecture.
That is a middleman in the problem.
It's just containerised windows or linux based on
a platform.
A microVM is a platform independent, platform agnostic.
It doesn't care about the platform.
It's a micro virtual machine on a platform.
I'm trying to cross the purpose of how
this works.
It works in an isolated environment, allows you
to swap and swap as a hot swap
services or hot swap features
or language features.
By plug, I mean literally you take it
up.
By plug, I mean you instal it, download
it, and by play, I mean you just
get started running in the native applicant in
the you want to use the web browser.
If the web browser is an environment, what
is a microVM doing in that environment?
It can use it to run simulations or
emulations of the environment.
But a microVM is an architectural principle of
the system.
It's a consideration of the architectural principle that
makes sure it's working the way it does.
How does it work practically?
You have a project workspace.
A project workspace is the root of the
project.
For example, you have a project name, project
name, four slides project name, but they share
the same name.
So a project name is a root folder
and the sub project name, project name is
a root folder.
The project workspace is the root folder and
operating workspace and the project name.
The project can be installed directly from the
project workspace because the project workspace is associated
with that project.
So let me have a workspace, four slides
project, that'll be a workspace name, four slides
project, and that'll be installable via the candidate
of the workspace.
Now, how does this ensure isolation?
It's a simple principle.
The project contains a source code, but you
have to zip the workspace, you have to
zip the project, you have to zip the
workspace.
Your goal is to zip the workspace and
by making the workspace an archive, you are
protecting it from the host environment.
The principle works because you can drag and
drop the folder of the zip folder.
So you have a project root, which is
the workspace, you have a project name, which
is the project name itself, and you have
the root divided by the workspace.
So you can enter the root, four slides,
root or workspace, four slides project name, and
putting them to be one project in the
workspace or one VM.
So how does this work?
The project contains the root source code and
the projects are services offered by the VM.
The VM is the VM or virtual machine,
it's actual root workspace that opens to the
commands everything.
So the workspace is a zip folder that
can be unpacked and that zip folder allows
you to run native, allows, gives a piece
of the system so you can have a
native shell or kernel, have some kind of
kernel implementation of a system.
So this is really a design principle for
hierarchical folders.
Use python-m pip instal workspace.projects or
project A or python-m pip instal workspace
.project2 or project B.
It isolates a web port.
For example, if you want to instal a
service here, you have a decentralised and distributed
model of doing this.
It's basically decentralised and distributed model.
It's like docker.
Basically, it's like docker because docker hosts, isolates
processes.
What a micro-vm does, docker contains projects
so they can run natively.
Docker is a container service, so docker can
spin up a windows container or a linux
container.
But what a micro-vm does is offer
or localise a native distributed virtual machine which
we call a micro-vm, a micro-virtual
machine to host the target of the system.
For example, you have this orchestration here.
You have the workspace root and of course,
we're going to do two packages, component A
and component B.
Now, component B exposes services to the, they
have component A.
Basically, the workspace is a process id and
the process id can start services.
So if the component A is a service,
the workspace starts that service of that component
and that is a native service that can
be on the server.
So the workspace is hosted on a server
as a zip instrument, as a zip archive.
And how you connect the system is by
making control by running the process id, by
hosting it with a process id.
The process can be any process.
Basically, it has a process id and the
process id has a service.
So component one represents a service.
Component two represents a service.
This can be package indexes of the same
system that runs a web component.
Applications are, you can run a modal, you
can run a service called a modal or
card, a card repository.
Basically, these are primitive ways to do it.
But you know, if you want to run
a modal, a modal component that registers the
real world telemetry, that without a polyglot system,
the zip will be installed and will be
on a server.
So it's a web service, basically.
So the web service is a server and
the web service will know that component A
and component one and two are packages or
native packages to Python, Node, JavaScript, you know,
that interact with the front-end function interface.
You can also consume shared object libraries or
WASM in real time, you know.
Don't have to wait for a new railroad
because anything in real time is allowed distributed
and distributed operation, you know.
And if it's an ISO service mesh that
can be used, such as peer-to-peer
-to-peer or three-peer-to-peer-to
-peer topology, for yes, no, and maybe, and
distributed governance workflow, you can have a terminal.
So applications like run a terminal in the
browser that's a micro-VM, because that terminal
goes into a system that can be controlled
by a command and control system.
So you can even use your own terminal
command and control system.
Like, you know, you reverse proxy a shell
to a service and that service is on
your computer.
So imagine two laptops, A and B, Alice's
laptop being controlled by Bob's laptop over the
IP protocol because the reverse shell being attached
to Alice's laptop and Bob can authenticate Alice,
like, you know, like a tax rabbit.
I prefer the term tax rabbit because tax
rabbits are the system one should use them
for.
So in all honesty, this is a primitive
version of the system.
As you can see here, you have a
workspace folder, root workspace A, subprocess A, subprocess
D, or you can have just two services.
This is a process ID for services.
This is from the web.
So this is service one and service two.
And this is working on a root workspace.
As you can see, the root workspace here
allows for, you know, the server to, you
know, this is just a package.
This is one package.
The components are exposed.
So this is a way you can plug
and play.
So we can plug in component one and
component two, which are basically used for micro
-VM isolation or component isolation in real time
in production development, you know.
But, you know, you can take any kind
of dynamic user language library and use it
because it's a platform.
You need to get any kind of build
library.
So there's a shared object library and expose
it to a native interface.
There's component one or two that consumes it
and delivers real-time feedback loop, kind of
cybersecurity feedback loop, to the system.
So, for example, if you're writing code, so
if you're writing, if you're writing code, you
have a real-time editor that shows people
how to code on the system, you know,
as they are typing it without including any
kind of artefacts, you know, because, you know,
the DLL can be consumed natively, but it's
because platform agnostic micro-virtualisation.
And it works in the browser.
This is my implementation of it.
So it's micro-agnostic.
It's a micro-agnostic system.
And this is the beauty of it.
So you can instal it directly and it
will work natively without any, so you can
extend it to Python or Node or Lua
or TypeScript or any language you so choose
and continue to develop.
It's called a micro-virtual machine.
It's a distributed way of working with artefacts,
with a native language artefact, a programming language
artefact.
Thank you for watching this video.